Hill'm Michael Siddi

ć iOS Developer

♠ hello@michaelsiddi.com

y @michaelsiddi

• Selargius, Italy

in www.linkedin.com/in/michaelsiddi

About Me

I'm a passionate software developer, geek and tech lover with 4+ years of professional iOS development experience. My code is present in the *beating heart* of more than 6 apps in the App Stores. One of them - indoona - has more than 1,5 million users and in 2013 it reached the first position the Italian Free Apps category.

Technical Skills

Objective-C, C, Java, Git, SVN, XMPP, WebRTC, PHP, iOS, XCode, Android, Eclipse, UIKit, Asynchronous Programming, Core Location, SQLite, Javascript.

Professional Experience

Lead Mobile Developer @ Vivocha | Startup | Oct. 2013 - Present

I'm the creator and maintainer of the Vivocha Mobile SDKs codebase.

The SDK provides a proactive Engagement button and a Chat view and only requires 2 lines of code for the basic integration. The new version I'm working on adds *voice* and *video* capabilities using WebRTC.

#iOS #Android #Objective-C #Java #XMPP #AFNetworking #WebRTC

iOS Developer @ **Tiscali** | *Italian Internet Service Provider* | Oct. 2012 - Oct. 2013 I was one of the three-member core team of indoona for iOS - a VoIP app with an integrated Twitter-like social network.

#iOS #Objective-C #XMPP #SIP #JSON

iOS & Android Consultant @ Tiscali | Apr. 2011 - Feb. 2012

Lead iOS Developer @ Zetesis | Feb. 2011 - Oct. 2012

I was in charge of the development and the release of 4 apps in the App Store.

#iOS #Objective-C #JSON #XML #MapKit #CoreLocation #Javascript

Education

Bachelor's Degree in **Computer Science** | *University of Cagliari* | 2006

♦ #C #OOP #Algorithms #Data-Structures #Java #Database

Other Projects

Contributor @ **Doubango** | *Open Source* | 2011 - 2012 | wrote some functions for the iOS demo app *iDoubs*.

Co-Founder @ **NetLife** | *Personal Project* | 2010

Other Information

Nationality: Italy

Thank you.